<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>PiinAlpin Official Blog</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/</link><description>Sharing is caring, keep learn and create an awesome codes.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:34:18 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://piinalpin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy Kubernetes Cluster on Vagrant With Ansible</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2024/03/deploy-kubernetes-on-vagrant-with-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:34:18 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2024/03/deploy-kubernetes-on-vagrant-with-ansible/</guid><description>The objective is describes the steps required to setup a multi node Kubernetes cluster for development purposes. This setup provides a production-like cluster that can be setup on your local machine. And we will use VirtualBox as the virtualization engine, Vagrant and Ansible for provisioning in our local environment. Before we setup kubernetes cluster, we need some prerequisities on our local machine below.
Oracle VM VirtualBox Vagrant Ansible Makesure you have setup network Host Only Adapter on your VirtualBox Why use Vagrant and Ansible?</description></item><item><title>Why Clean Code is Important?</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2023/12/why-clean-code-is-important/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 09:59:23 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2023/12/why-clean-code-is-important/</guid><description>What is Clean Code? Clean code is term used to refer to code that easy to read, understand, and maintain. The goals of clean code is to create software that is not only functional but also readable, maintainable, and eficient throughout its lifecycle which can save time and reduce the risk of introducing errors.
Benefits of Clean Code Readability: Clean code is easy to read and understand, making it easier to maintain, debug and update.</description></item><item><title>Build Kie Server on Spring Boot</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2023/12/build-kie-server-on-spring-boot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:49:12 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2023/12/build-kie-server-on-spring-boot/</guid><description>jBPM is a toolkit for building business applications to help automate business processes and decisions.
jBPM originates from BPM (Business Process Management) but it has evolved to enable users to pick their own path in business automation. It provides various capabilities that simplify and externalize business logic into reusable assets such as cases, processes, decision tables and more.
business processes (BPMN2) case management (BPMN2 and CMMN) decision management (DMN) business rules (DRL) business optimisation (Solver) jBPM can be used as standalone service or embedded in custom service.</description></item><item><title>Make Terminal Powerfull Using Oh-My-Posh</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2023/11/make-terminal-powerfull-using-oh-my-posh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 18:36:21 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2023/11/make-terminal-powerfull-using-oh-my-posh/</guid><description>Programmers use a command-line interface (CLI) to issue text-commands to the Operating System (OS), instead of clicking on a Graphical User Interface (GUI). This is because command-line inerface is much more powerful and flexible than the graphical user interface.
The Terminal application is a command-line Interface (or shell). By default, the Terminal in Ubuntu and macOS runs the so-called bash shell, which supports a set of commands and utilities; and has its own programming language for writing shell scripts.</description></item><item><title>Spring Boot TCP Integration IP</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2023/06/spring-boot-tcp-integration-ip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:29:10 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2023/06/spring-boot-tcp-integration-ip/</guid><description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a communications standard that enables application programs and computing devices to exchange messages over a network. It is designed to send packets across the internet and ensure the successful delivery of data and messages over networks.
TCP is one of the basic standards that define the rules of the internet and is included within the standards defined by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). It is one of the most commonly used protocols within digital network communications and ensures end-to-end data delivery.</description></item><item><title>High Availability with Redis Sentinel and Spring Lettuce Client</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/10/redis-sentinel-spring-lettuce-client/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:48:09 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/10/redis-sentinel-spring-lettuce-client/</guid><description>Redis is an open source (BSD licensed), in-memory data structure store used as a database, cache, message broker, and streaming engine. Redis provides data structures such as strings, hashes, lists, sets, sorted sets with range queries, bitmaps, hyperloglogs, geospatial indexes, and streams. Redis has built-in replication, Lua scripting, LRU eviction, transactions, and different levels of on-disk persistence, and provides high availability via Redis Sentinel and automatic partitioning with Redis Cluster.</description></item><item><title>How to Run Redis Sentinel</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/10/how-to-run-redis-sentinel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:02:54 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/10/how-to-run-redis-sentinel/</guid><description>Redis Sentinel is the high-availability solution for open-source Redis server. It provides monitoring of all Redis nodes and automatic failover should the master node become unavailable. This guide provides a sample configuration for a three-node Redis cluster.
Sentinel itself is designed to run in a configuration where there are multiple Sentinel processes cooperating together. The advantage of having multiple Sentinel processes cooperating are the following :
Failure detection is performed when multiple Sentinels agree about the fact a given master is no longer available.</description></item><item><title>Salary Prediction with ML - Linear Regression</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/05/salary-prediction-with-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 17:07:17 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/05/salary-prediction-with-machine-learning/</guid><description>Machine learning is a branch of artificial intelligence (AI) and computer science which focuses on the use of data and algorithms to imitate the way that humans learn, gradually improving its accuracy.
How Does Machine Learning Works? Similar to how the human brain gains knowledge and understanding, machine learning relies on input, such as training data or knowledge graphs, to understand entities, domains and the connections between them. With entities defined, deep learning can begin.</description></item><item><title>Api Gateway Using Spring Boot Cloud Gateway + Netflix Hystrix</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/api-gateway-using-spring-boot-cloud-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 13:38:40 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/api-gateway-using-spring-boot-cloud-gateway/</guid><description>An API gateway is an interface between clients and backend microservices. When a gateway is used, it becomes the single point of contact for clients; it receives their API calls and routes each one to the appropriate backend.
It facilitates microservice architectures. When an API gateway is used, clients do not know (nor should they know) the structure of the backend. Modern architectures discourage the use of large monolithic services; rather, numerous small microservices are preferred.</description></item><item><title>CI/CD Using Github Action</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/ci-cd-using-github-action/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:28:28 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/ci-cd-using-github-action/</guid><description>Continuous integration is a coding philosophy and set of practices that drive development teams to frequently implement small code changes and check them in to a version control repository. Most modern applications require developing code using a variety of platforms and tools, so teams need a consistent mechanism to integrate and validate changes. Continuous integration establishes an automated way to build, package, and test their applications. Having a consistent integration process encourages developers to commit code changes more frequently, which leads to better collaboration and code quality.</description></item></channel></rss>