<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>PiinAlpin&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/</link>
        <description>Sharing is caring, keep learn and create an awesome codes.</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 13:28:42 &#43;0700</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://blog.piinalpin.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>JPA Soft Deletes Implementation - Spring Boot</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/jpa-soft-deletes-implementation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 13:28:42 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/jpa-soft-deletes-implementation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Implementing custom jpa soft deletes because sometimes there are business requirements to not permanently delete data from the database.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Best Practice Uploading File Using Spring RestTemplate</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/best-practice-uploading-file-using-rest-template/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 14:11:02 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/best-practice-uploading-file-using-rest-template/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A little things but important when uploading files through REST template. It should send the filename in the correct format.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Image Processing Using Tensorflow - Convolutional Neural Network (CNN)</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/image-processing-using-tensorflow/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 10:02:39 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/image-processing-using-tensorflow/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Digital image processing is the use of a digital computer to process digital images through an algorithm. As a subcategory or field of digital signal processing, digital image processing has many advantages over analog image processing.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Object Relational Mapping Node JS using Sequelize</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/orm-nodejs-sequelize/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 10:31:30 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/orm-nodejs-sequelize/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) is a technique that lets you query and manipulate data from a database using an object-oriented paradigm.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Cloud Object Storage Spring Boot With Minio</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/cloud-object-storage-spring-boot-with-minio/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 09:55:34 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/cloud-object-storage-spring-boot-with-minio/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[MinIO is a High Performance Object Storage released under GNU Affero General Public License v3.0. It is API compatible with Amazon S3 cloud storage service. Use MinIO to build high performance infrastructure for machine learning, analytics and application data workloads.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Spring Boot Web Socket Chat Bot</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/spring-boot-web-socket-chat-bot/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:52:27 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/spring-boot-web-socket-chat-bot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Build real time chat with bot using spring boot web socket and contextual chat bot python.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Contextual Chat Bot using NLP</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/contextual-chat-bot/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 11:19:26 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/contextual-chat-bot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Build contextual chat bot with python and tensorflow library to talking about riddles. We will build a model for a puzzle conversation.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Bash Script for Lazy People</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/bash-script-for-lazy-people/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 15:13:17 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/bash-script-for-lazy-people/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is Bash? Bash is a command processor that typically runs in a text window where the user types commands that cause actions. Bash can also read and execute commands from a file, called a shell script. Like most Unix shells, it supports filename globbing (wildcard matching), piping, here documents, command substitution, variables, and control structures for condition-testing and iteration. The keywords, syntax, dynamically scoped variables and other basic features of the language are all copied from sh.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>My Docker Compose Collection</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/docker-compose-collection/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 20:01:28 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/docker-compose-collection/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Basic command 1 2  docker-compose -f $FILENAME up -d docker-compose -f $FILENAME down -v   Kafka CLI Download docker compose configuration using curl
1  curl -o kafka-cli.yaml https://raw.githubusercontent.com/piinalpin/docker-compose-collection/master/kafka-cli.yaml   This yaml kafka-cli.yaml will create a new container zookeeper and exposed port 2181 on host port. Also create a new container kafka and exposed port 29092, 9092 and 9101 on host port.
Redis By default there are 16 databases (indexed from 0 to 15) and you can navigate between them using select command.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Install Jenkins on Centos7</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/install-jenkins-on-centos7/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 09:38:14 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/install-jenkins-on-centos7/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview Jenkins is a self-contained, open source automation server which can be used to automate all sorts of tasks related to building, testing, and delivering or deploying software.
Jenkins can be installed through native system packages, Docker, or even run standalone by any machine with a Java Runtime Environment (JRE) installed (Jenkins.io).
Prerequisites  Vagrant, see how to install Vagrant here Add the following host entries on local device /etc/hosts : 1 2  192.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
