<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Kubernetes - Tag - PiinAlpin Official Blog</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Kubernetes - Tag - PiinAlpin Official Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 11:09:25 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://piinalpin.com/tags/kubernetes/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Fix Kubernetes DNS Redirect to External on Proxmox</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2024/08/how-to-fix-kubernetes-dns-redirect-to-external-on-proxmox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 11:09:25 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2024/08/how-to-fix-kubernetes-dns-redirect-to-external-on-proxmox/</guid><description>What Happened?
I want deploy spring boot microservices and I have services called dexter and enclave and want communicate to each other using REST. They can communicate if I set service url using container hostname which is dexter and enclave. But somehow they won&amp;rsquo;t communicate if I use Fully Qualified Domain Name (FQDN) on kubernetes and got 302 Found. Seems redirect to external domain on public network which should not be registered.</description></item><item><title>Build Kubernetes Cluster on Proxmox VE</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2024/07/build-kubernetes-cluster-on-proxmox-ve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 08:44:46 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2024/07/build-kubernetes-cluster-on-proxmox-ve/</guid><description>The documentation is describing the steps required to setup kubernetes cluster on bare metal using command line step by steps. We will need:
At least 2 ubuntu server instance, can use 18.04 or 22.04. We will made this using single cluster with 1 instance kubernetes controller and another as node instance. Make sure all instance has static IP address, you can use Terraform to create instance on this tutorial on proxmox.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Kubernetes on Proxmox using K3S</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2024/04/deploy-kubernetes-production-ready-on-proxmox-using-k3s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 11:21:12 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2024/04/deploy-kubernetes-production-ready-on-proxmox-using-k3s/</guid><description>The documentation is describing the steps required to setup kubernetes cluster using K3S and learning automation provisioning using Terraform and Ansible on Proxmox VE. Before we setup kubernetes cluster, we need some prerequisities below.
Proxmox VE Ansible Terraform Disclaimer : I use WiFi network for my homelab server, you can check this documentation Setup Proxmox With Wireless Interface - My Homelab.
Setup Cloud Init Template This step is describe how to create cloud init template for provide provisioning virtual machine template on proxmox.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Kubernetes Cluster on Vagrant With Ansible</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2024/03/deploy-kubernetes-on-vagrant-with-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:34:18 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2024/03/deploy-kubernetes-on-vagrant-with-ansible/</guid><description>The objective is describes the steps required to setup a multi node Kubernetes cluster for development purposes. This setup provides a production-like cluster that can be setup on your local machine. And we will use VirtualBox as the virtualization engine, Vagrant and Ansible for provisioning in our local environment. Before we setup kubernetes cluster, we need some prerequisities on our local machine below.
Oracle VM VirtualBox Vagrant Ansible Makesure you have setup network Host Only Adapter on your VirtualBox Why use Vagrant and Ansible?</description></item><item><title>Persistent Volume and Persistent Volume Claim in Kubernetes</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes-pv-and-pvc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 09:37:50 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes-pv-and-pvc/</guid><description>Managing storage is a distinct problem from managing compute instances. The PersistentVolume subsystem provides an API for users and administrators that abstracts details of how storage is provided from how it is consumed. To do this, we introduce two new API resources: PersistentVolume and PersistentVolumeClaim.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kubernetes</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 09:19:24 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes/</guid><description>Kubernetes, also known as K8s, is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.</description></item></channel></rss>