<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>DevOps - Tag - PiinAlpin&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/tags/devops/</link>
        <description>DevOps - Tag - PiinAlpin&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:28:28 &#43;0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.piinalpin.com/tags/devops/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>CI/CD Using Github Action</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2022/04/ci-cd-using-github-action/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:28:28 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2022/04/ci-cd-using-github-action/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Continuous integration is a coding philosophy and set of practices that drive development teams to frequently implement small code changes and check them in to a version control repository. Most modern applications require developing code using a variety of platforms and tools, so teams need a consistent mechanism to integrate and validate changes. Continuous integration establishes an automated way to build, package, and test their applications. Having a consistent integration process encourages developers to commit code changes more frequently, which leads to better collaboration and code quality.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Install Jenkins on Centos7</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/08/install-jenkins-on-centos7/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 09:38:14 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/08/install-jenkins-on-centos7/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview Jenkins is a self-contained, open source automation server which can be used to automate all sorts of tasks related to building, testing, and delivering or deploying software.
Jenkins can be installed through native system packages, Docker, or even run standalone by any machine with a Java Runtime Environment (JRE) installed (Jenkins.io).
Prerequisites  Vagrant, see how to install Vagrant here Add the following host entries on local device /etc/hosts : 1 2  192.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why Should Learn Ansible - Linux Automation</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/07/why-should-learn-ansible/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 19:26:29 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/07/why-should-learn-ansible/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview Ansible is a radically simple IT automation engine that automates cloud provisioning, configuration management, application deployment, intra-service orchestration, and many other IT needs.
Designed for multi-tier deployments since day one, Ansible models your IT infrastructure by describing how all of your systems inter-relate, rather than just managing one system at a time.
It uses no agents and no additional custom security infrastructure, so it&rsquo;s easy to deploy - and most importantly, it uses a very simple language (YAML, in the form of Ansible Playbooks) that allow you to describe your automation jobs in a way that approaches plain English.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Persistent Volume and Persistent Volume Claim in Kubernetes</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes-pv-and-pvc/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 09:37:50 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes-pv-and-pvc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Managing storage is a distinct problem from managing compute instances. The PersistentVolume subsystem provides an API for users and administrators that abstracts details of how storage is provided from how it is consumed. To do this, we introduce two new API resources: PersistentVolume and PersistentVolumeClaim.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Learning Kubernetes</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 09:19:24 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-kubernetes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Kubernetes, also known as K8s, is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why Should Learn Docker</title>
    <link>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-docker/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:57:27 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://blog.piinalpin.com/2021/05/why-should-learn-docker/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Docker takes away repetitive, mundane configuration tasks and is used throughout the development lifecycle for fast, easy and portable application development - desktop and cloud. Docker’s comprehensive end to end platform includes UIs, CLIs, APIs and security that are engineered to work together across the entire application delivery lifecycle.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
