<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Spring Boot - Tag - PiinAlpin Official Blog</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/tags/spring-boot/</link><description>Spring Boot - Tag - PiinAlpin Official Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:49:12 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://piinalpin.com/tags/spring-boot/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build Kie Server on Spring Boot</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2023/12/build-kie-server-on-spring-boot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:49:12 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2023/12/build-kie-server-on-spring-boot/</guid><description>jBPM is a toolkit for building business applications to help automate business processes and decisions.
jBPM originates from BPM (Business Process Management) but it has evolved to enable users to pick their own path in business automation. It provides various capabilities that simplify and externalize business logic into reusable assets such as cases, processes, decision tables and more.
business processes (BPMN2) case management (BPMN2 and CMMN) decision management (DMN) business rules (DRL) business optimisation (Solver) jBPM can be used as standalone service or embedded in custom service.</description></item><item><title>Spring Boot TCP Integration IP</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2023/06/spring-boot-tcp-integration-ip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:29:10 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2023/06/spring-boot-tcp-integration-ip/</guid><description>Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a communications standard that enables application programs and computing devices to exchange messages over a network. It is designed to send packets across the internet and ensure the successful delivery of data and messages over networks.
TCP is one of the basic standards that define the rules of the internet and is included within the standards defined by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). It is one of the most commonly used protocols within digital network communications and ensures end-to-end data delivery.</description></item><item><title>High Availability with Redis Sentinel and Spring Lettuce Client</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/10/redis-sentinel-spring-lettuce-client/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 13:48:09 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/10/redis-sentinel-spring-lettuce-client/</guid><description>Redis is an open source (BSD licensed), in-memory data structure store used as a database, cache, message broker, and streaming engine. Redis provides data structures such as strings, hashes, lists, sets, sorted sets with range queries, bitmaps, hyperloglogs, geospatial indexes, and streams. Redis has built-in replication, Lua scripting, LRU eviction, transactions, and different levels of on-disk persistence, and provides high availability via Redis Sentinel and automatic partitioning with Redis Cluster.</description></item><item><title>Api Gateway Using Spring Boot Cloud Gateway + Netflix Hystrix</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/api-gateway-using-spring-boot-cloud-gateway/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 13:38:40 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/api-gateway-using-spring-boot-cloud-gateway/</guid><description>An API gateway is an interface between clients and backend microservices. When a gateway is used, it becomes the single point of contact for clients; it receives their API calls and routes each one to the appropriate backend.
It facilitates microservice architectures. When an API gateway is used, clients do not know (nor should they know) the structure of the backend. Modern architectures discourage the use of large monolithic services; rather, numerous small microservices are preferred.</description></item><item><title>Searching And Filtering Using JPA Specification - Spring Boot</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/searching-and-filtering-using-jpa-specification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 06:53:17 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/04/searching-and-filtering-using-jpa-specification/</guid><description>Introduction Spring data JPA provides many ways to deal with entities including query methods and custom JPQL queries. However, sometimes we need a more programmatic approach: for example Criteria API or QueryDSL.
Spring Data JPA Specification provides a convenient and sophisticated manner to build dynamic SQL where clauses. By adding some extra logic and considering some pitfalls, we are capable of offering API consumers a zero-effort generic mechanism for filtering entities.</description></item><item><title>JPA Soft Deletes Implementation - Spring Boot</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/03/jpa-soft-deletes-implementation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 13:28:42 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/03/jpa-soft-deletes-implementation/</guid><description>Implementing custom jpa soft deletes because sometimes there are business requirements to not permanently delete data from the database.</description></item><item><title>Best Practice Uploading File Using Spring RestTemplate</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2022/02/best-practice-uploading-file-using-rest-template/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 14:11:02 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2022/02/best-practice-uploading-file-using-rest-template/</guid><description>A little things but important when uploading files through REST template. It should send the filename in the correct format.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Object Storage Spring Boot With Minio</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2021/11/cloud-object-storage-spring-boot-with-minio/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 09:55:34 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2021/11/cloud-object-storage-spring-boot-with-minio/</guid><description>MinIO is a High Performance Object Storage released under GNU Affero General Public License v3.0. It is API compatible with Amazon S3 cloud storage service. Use MinIO to build high performance infrastructure for machine learning, analytics and application data workloads.</description></item><item><title>Spring Boot Web Socket Chat Bot</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2021/10/spring-boot-web-socket-chat-bot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:52:27 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2021/10/spring-boot-web-socket-chat-bot/</guid><description>Build real time chat with bot using spring boot web socket and contextual chat bot python.</description></item><item><title>Messaging on Kafka-CLI With Spring Boot</title><link>https://piinalpin.com/2021/07/messaging-on-kafka-with-spring-boot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:04:22 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://piinalpin.com/2021/07/messaging-on-kafka-with-spring-boot/</guid><description>Overview Kafka is a distributed system consisting of servers and clients that communicate via a high-performance TCP network protocol. It can be deployed on bare-metal hardware, virtual machines, and containers in on-premise as well as cloud environments.
Servers: Kafka is run as a cluster of one or more servers that can span multiple datacenters or cloud regions. Some of these servers form the storage layer, called the brokers. Other servers run Kafka Connect to continuously import and export data as event streams to integrate Kafka with your existing systems such as relational databases as well as other Kafka clusters.</description></item></channel></rss>